Hello friends, I welcome you to your
YouTube channel. When the results are announced, we
will check how the results came out. Also, whether the
results met the market expectations or
not. All these things will be checked. You
can see the results are in front of you.
Whatever numbers we will discuss, the
comparison will be done on a yearly and quarterly basis. You
can see this result. This is your
last year's result of 2023. This
company announced the result today. This is your
previous quarter's result. And since
this is a bank, the first thing you have to know is what they earned,
like
interest earned, what kind of interest,
discount, interest income. After adding all of them,
see the interest earned. You can see how much it is.
Here it is seen that it has
just come to 4632. Last year it was
389380. There is a good jump in the rate yearly. It has
increased from 4458 to 4635 on a quarterly basis. You
can see here also that a great
jump is being seen. Yearly end
Now see on quarterly basis, add all here,
interest earned, other income,
add all then it will become total income which is
coming now, 72942 is seen here,
last year it was 5729,
check it year on year, you can see here a jump of 2727 is seen, on
quarterly basis it has increased from 6727 to
7294, here also a jump of 8% is seen,
now see
how much was spent in generating this income,
what is the expense, it is also being told to be 5364, last
year it was 41000, year on year the expense
i.e. expenses have also increased significantly and on
quarterly basis it has increased from 4912 to 53, that is the
expense is the highest till date,
seen here, if you subtract this income
from the expense then your operating profit will
come before provision, before provision,
this is your operating profit before making provision  There
is profit of 1987 also, last year it was
1547, so there is a good jump year after year in
profit as well, in operating profit on
end quarterly basis it is
18777, so far the results are looking very good,
now see, in this we will
subtract the provision, provision is that money which the
company keeps aside if the bank feels that it is risky money and it
can sink,
so see here it is being told
how much has been done now, 1381 is being kept aside, you can
see the last rate was 649, so you can see
in provisioning, there is a good
jump which has become negative
for the bank, here on quarterly
basis it has increased from 13 10315 to 1, that is, on
yearly end quarterly basis the provisional
provisioning is increasing
which has become negative, here now
in this operating profit, now
subtract the provisioning, subtract the tax, so
after subtracting everything, your
net profit is coming out, that is yours  It is
also being reported to be 12947. Last year it was 1089.6.
If you check, year on year a
jump of about 19 is being seen. And on
quarterly basis it has increased from 11695 to 12947.
Here also a jump of 11 is being seen. If you
check the EPS, it is also of 18.3.
Last year it was 15.5. You can see year on year
jump in EPS. Quarterly
basis EPS has increased from 16.6.4 to 18.3. Here we can move
ahead and
check the NPA of the company as well.
See the NPA which is being reported. Ah, you
can see it here. If we check the NPA gross NPA
first, then see the gross NPA is being
reported here. In terms of percentage, it has
also come to 1.97. Last year it was 2.48.
That means there is a good improvement in the asset quality.
NPA is falling, so there is a
decline year on year.  It is good that on quarterly
basis it has fallen from 2.15 to 1.97, so we are seeing
improvement in asset quality. If we
check the percentage of net non-performing asset on yearly and quarterly basis, then it is being reported to be 0.42,
last year it was 0.43, there
is a slight decline in this as well, we
can also see on quarterly basis, a decline is being seen here, so there is
improvement in quality,
hence let's move ahead, we will
also check their net interest income and plus
margin, whether market estimator has been done
or not, all these things will be checked,
see if we check the net interest income, it has
increased, it is increasing to
99.5 year on year basis to 20048,
here we can
see that net interest income is seeing a decline, earlier it was
4.36, here it has fallen to 4.27, so
here two things are seen negative,
one is provisioning.  The
second one is the net interest margin which is increasing and a
dip is being seen in it, so two
things are getting negative here right now, let's move
ahead, we can see that the
provisioning which is there has also increased and is
increasing, it is being told to be 1233,
last it was 583, so it increased from 583 to
1233 and apart from that
profit after tax has grown by 14.5, so
11746 is seen here, now let's move ahead, did
this result beat the market
estimators or not, it is being told here that for any
bank quarter to quarter net
profit jumps 14 on year to 11746, it
beats street estimates, so in terms of profit
it has beaten, let's move ahead, whether it
beat in terms of revenue
or not, let's check that, we
can see here, the
revenue which has come just now, we had an expectation of 2048 crores, you
can see that it was
of 2845, so it has missed the money control period  It was an
average, it did not meet it, you
can see it in terms of revenue, the same
thing is explained here in the table form,
check the entire brokerage, MK Global Share
Khan Access Security and Security,
check everything, so the average here in terms of revenue is
2845,
how much did it come, 20 3048, so it has
not been met in terms of revenue, you can see and if you
check in terms of profit, it has come
11746, the expectation was 10989, so it has been
met in terms of profit, you can see it has
not been met in terms of revenue, and it has been
met in terms of profit, along with this, the
provisioning which is there is increasing,
which has become negative, and at the same time, a
dip is also being seen in the margin, so many
things are negative, many things are
positive, so a mixed
kind of result was seen here,
everything will depend on the market
environment, so this was the complete up
regarding II Bank result, I hope you
liked the video.  If you like the video, please
like, share and
subscribe to the channel. Thank you.